WWW.52HALFCD.COM
时代影视论坛 荣誉出品
影片压制&字幕制作：liubinqing
方丈
Abbot,
有个女人在庙外边扔下一个孩子
a woman has left a baby outside the temple
那么那个女人是谁？
who was that woman?
就是村里面疯婆子
The mad woman of the village
那她现在人呢？
where is she now?
死在外边了
She died outside
那你赶快叫人去把她埋了
Bury her quickly
然后念经超渡
and then pray for her soul
那么这个小孩子呢？
what about the baby?
这孩子弃入我寺就是与佛有缘
Destiny has bid him come to us
把他留在庙里吧
keep him in the temple
小孩，既然来到这个世界
Son, since you have been born in the world
就要承担世上一切的苦难
you must bear its sufferings
为什么还哭得那么伤心呢？
why cry so sadly?
你看，小疯子又偷懒了
Look, the Crazy kid is slacking off again
走，去告诉师父
Go, tell the teacher
师父，你看，他又不干活
Look, teacher, he's not working again
小疯子
Crazy kid
师父
Teacher
你在这儿干什么？
what are you doing here?
那条绳松了，我把它绑紧
I am tightening the rope
快点弄好它，勤快点做事
Fix it and go to work
小疯子
Crazy kid
二十年前有人把你抛弃在这儿
20 years ago you were abandoned here
结果我们把你抱进来养育你
and we raised you
我知道
I know
而且我还知道我妈是一个疯子
I also know that my mom was a lunatic
所以个个都叫我小疯子
and hence my name
那么现在你觉得
Then how do you feel
在我们庙里面怎么样？
about living in the temple?
没有什么，我也不知道
I don't know
但是我不明白
But I don't understand
为什么这儿的人老是跟你过不去
why people here can't get along with you
是啊，为什么老欺侮我？
Yes, why do they always bully me?
这都是因为你不识时务的关系
It's because you aren't tactful enough with them
不过我又觉得你很勤力练功
However, I feel you are working hard on your kung fu
是啊，他们不肯教我
Right, they wouldn't teach me
我只有自己悄悄地练
so I practise alone
那么我单独教你一套拳
Then I'll teach you a fist style
你真的肯教我？
Really?
师父，你教我什么拳？
What will you teach me?
就是本门所创的十八罗汉拳
Our 18 Lohans fist
真的？
Really?
这套拳法好难、好高深
It is very difficult
而且威力很大
but it's very powerful
为了你将来生存于世
For your future
我想好好的教会了你
I want to teach you well
一手比力一手举，一上一下把身起
One hand uses power, the other lifts;
两腿肚进腰接力，燕儿含泥身不低
Power to the hips and legs, just like a swallow dipping
方寸捺定一口气，两手左右上下劈
steady your breath while both hands chop up & down
浑身使尽不同力，凝目全神屏气息
power throughout the body, focus your energy
犀牛望月挥双手，翻身扭腰胸前阻
move your hands as a rhinoceros, flip & turn your body
头部抬高鼻担息，一出英武及双眸
lift head, deep breath; vigor scintillating from eyes
环转须用两腿力，提气呼吸收在口
turn with your legs, breathe through your mouth
提气力极壮筋骨，开合收臂鸾凤舞
the Chi will strengthen bones and ligaments,
撑腿合手蹬满力，挺胸眼敛似雷鼓
power in the arms & legs, chest out as you dance about
与德同效脱武力，四肢奇功要勤苦
By hard training your limbs would be strengthened
小疯子
Crazy kid
你们叫我干什么？
what?
你说你这两个月
You said in these 2 months
跟师父学的那套拳的威力
you have learnt invincible fist skills
是天下无敌的，是不是？
from teacher, right?
天下无敌？什么天下无敌？
What are you talking about?
我没有说过
I never said that
还说没有，明明是你说的，是吗？
You did
是，你还要骗我们
Right, you still want to lie to us
我没有说过
I never said that
你还想赖，好，给你点厉害看看
Alright, I'll teach you a lesson
真是欺人太甚了
You push too far
住手，小疯子，不要打人了
Stop fighting
小疯子，你在庙里不守清规
Crazy kid, you hit your senior and
打师兄、成天吊儿郎当
do nothing all day
本来我不会怪你
Still, I wouldn't have blamed you
但是庙里所有的人都不能容忍你
but others in the temple can't tolerate you
所以经过我们几个人的研究
So after discussing this
你还是离开这儿下山去的好
we think you'd better leave
我？下山？
Me? Leave?
去看看世俗的一切
Go and see the world
那些地方或者会比较适合你
there may be a place more suitable for you
师父
Teacher
但是你要记住
But bear this in mind
佛门广大，慈悲为怀
teachings of Buddhism are magnificent and compassionate
如果你想回头随时都可以回来
In case you want to come back, please do so
这就是我们的意思，你想想吧
This is our wish, think about it
快…
Hurry...
你们到处抢劫，成何体统？
How could you go about robbing?
老家伙，这儿轮不到你讲话
Shut up, old man
你识相点还是快点走吧
Get lost if you are smart
小福禄，你仗著你父亲的权势
Xiao Fu Lu, you use your father's power
在镇上无恶不作，欺压良民
to oppress the people
这儿是你的吗？
is this your territory?
欺压良民怎么样？
So what if I oppress the people?
你最好是少管闲事
You'd better not meddle in my affairs
岂有此理，你们怎么可以这样做呢
Damn, how could you do that?
这并不是抢
This is not robbery
是我们王老爷让我们来
Master wang has merely asked us to take back
拿点金银珠宝回去给他欣赏一下
some jewelry for him to admire
走…去你的
Move away
我们走
Let's go
走开…听见没有，走开
Make way, hear that? Clear the way
上路了
Set off
小黑子，不能去，快回来…
Xiao Hei, don't go
你们不应该打家劫舍
You shouldn't rob
我问你，你有没有良心？
Don't you have any conscience?
好小子，跑到这儿管闲事来了
Damn kid, poking your nose in our business
我问你，关你什么事？
what concern is it of yours?
不关我事，我看不过眼
I can't let this matter pass
看不过眼？我对你也看不过眼，上
I can't let you live either, attack
喂…别打了
Stop fighting
别打了
好了好了，别打了，上路了
Stop fighting, let's go
王老爷等著这批货，走
Master wang is waiting for us, let's go...
走…
Let's go
这位大师…
Master...
请问大师来自何方？
May I ask where you are from?
我四海为家，居无定所
I am just a wanderer
那好极了
Great
我见到大师锄强扶弱，很有义气
You are a righteous person and help the weak
没什么
Nothing much
不如请大师到镇上走一走
why don't you come to our town?
到镇上？好，好极了
That'd be great
请…
Please...
大师，我们镇上的百姓
Our people have since long
经常受到恶人的欺负
been oppressed by bad elements
大师武艺高强
Your kung fu is so good
不知道大师能不能够留在镇上
I wonder if you could stay
帮帮我们
in our town and help us
留在镇上？是真的吗？
You mean that?
尹三爷在我们镇上
Mr. Yin is our most
是最受尊敬的长辈
respected senior in town
平生都为百姓著想
and always thinks about the interest of our people
他老人家说的每一句话
His every word
可以说是一言九鼎
carries a lot of credibility
是啊
Right
我们三爷是有意思
He sincerely wants you
想把大师留在镇上
to stay in town
大师不妨考虑考虑
Please consider
那没关系，反正我也是刚刚下山的
That's okay, I just got here
可以说是无家可归的
and have no place to stay
既然三爷肯留我在镇上
Since I am invited
那真是好极了
that's opportune
我们都希望你能够留下来
we all hope you could stay
不知道你还擅长什么？
what else are you good at?
我？我什么都会
Well, I know lots of things
好极了，反正就是缺少一间素菜馆
Great, all we need is a vegetarian restaurant
不如我们合资开一间菜馆
let's go into partnership and open one
请大师主持好不好？
And you're gonna be the chef, okay?
对了，我也赞成
I support that
素菜馆？
A vegetarian restaurant?
对了，大师这个你是最内行了
Right, it's indeed your specialty
不知道你有没有兴趣呢？
what do you think?
有，我什么菜都会做
Yes, I could make many dishes
而且是一流的
and they are all tasty
就是不知道对不对你们的胃口
I only wonder if they suit your taste
你们吃了要是有什么三长两短的
If anything happens to you after you eat them
可别怪我
don't blame me
"Lohan Vegetarian Restaurant"
谢谢…
Thank you...
尹三爷，恭喜你生意兴隆财源广进
I wish you every success in your business
各位邻居，这间素菜馆
Neighbours, this vegetarian restaurant
是由我们疯大师亲自主持的
is run by our Master Crazy
各位以后多多光顾
so please honour us with your patronage
各位请进来试一试，尝一尝
Come in and try
我请…
My treat...
一流…
Great...
这素菜真不错
It's really good
里边请…
Inside please...
几位走了？慢走…谢谢
Bye. Thank you
阿龙，你困了？
Ah Long, are you sleepy?
半夜三更了还不困？
Yes, of course
这阵子快闷死我了
I feel so bored
闷什么？
How come?
现在有事做总比以前到处流浪好
It's better to have ajob now
我说还是以前日子好
But I still think the old days were better
难道你喜欢跟那帮流氓混在一起？
Do you prefer being around with
好过瘾吗？
those bums?
最低限度有得吃有得玩
Um, at least it used to be more fun
不像现在这么死板板的
Now it's so mechanical
现在有什么死板的？
what mechanical?
还不死板？
You don't think so?
整天在这儿吃饭睡觉干活
We work, eat and sleep
一个月连一天休息都没有
and don't even have a day off in a month
我看就快做和尚了
It's like being a monk
阿龙…
Ah Long...
什么事？
Yes?
有没有钱？
Do you have money?
当然没有
Of course not
那惨了，我一个钱都没有
I haven't a dime too
你叫我怎么做人呢？
how could I live like this?
半夜三更的还做什么人，真是
It's late at night
阿龙
Ah Long
你睡吧，我出去走走
Good night, I'll take a walk
我要找姑娘…
Oh man, I want a girl...
不要吵…别吵…
Quiet, please...
小少爷你不用叫
Little master, stay calm
你喜欢哪个姑娘？
which girl do you like?
要我…
Pick me...
这个，那个，还有这个
That one, this one and her
小少爷，叫了这么多怎么行？
So many?
当心消化不良
You might not be able to take it
几个还不够，最好来一打
It's better to have a dozen
别吵，好了
Alright
小少爷，你要叫多少就叫多少
Have it your way
没一打也有半打
Let me bring you half a dozen for the time being
我还要吃鱼翅、鲍鱼和炖鸡
And some expensive cuisine too
小少爷你真懂得吃，进来吧
You really know your food, come in
快进来
Come in quickly
这不是小黑
This is Xiao Hei
是啊，这小子不是在
Doesn't he work
小疯子菜馆里面当跑堂的
as a waiter in Crazy kid's vegetarian restaurant?
他哪来这么多钱？
How can he have money to pay the bill?
不对，快去报告王老爷去
Let's report this to master wang
好，我们去
Right, let's go
什么？
what?
一个跑堂的竟敢在这里大吃大喝的
A waiter is feasting here?
是啊，他派头还挺大的
Yes, he's also
叫了一打姑娘
booked a dozen girls
还要吃鱼翅鲍鱼炖鸡
and wants to eat shark's fin and chicken
有点问题，你们先下去看看
Something's wrong, go and take a look
别吵，你们别吵了
Stop this noise
别吵了
Quiet
全给我走开
Go away
小少爷，我们这儿的规矩
It's our rule
请你先把账付了
that you should pay first
付账？付什么账？
Pay what?
你在这儿大吃大喝
You are feasting here
又要了那么多的姑娘
and have booked so many girls
难道我们是不要本钱的吗？
we have a business to run here
我是叫了这么多姑娘
I booked many girls
可是我没上过床
but not yet gone to bed with any
是，不过如果上了床
Yes, but if you did
不是全给了你了
wouldn't you have enjoyed a free ride?
全给我又怎么样？
So what?
你以为我不要本钱？神经病
You think I don't have costs for my business?
所以我们想让你先付了账
You'll have to pay first
一共是三十六两银票
36 taels altogether
三十六两银票？你们想抢劫？
So expensive! You want to rob me?
别耍赖，请你先付账
Come on, pay up first
我没有银票
I don't have it
那你有什么？
what do you have then?
让我问你，你身上到底有些什么？
What do you have on you?
我有拳头
My fists
什么话？
what?
讲的是人话
You heard me
慢著
wait
我们这儿的规矩是不打客人的
Our rules are that we don't strike customers
把他拉上警察局
Take him to the authorities
走…
Let's go...
王老爷，那个小子给警察抓了去
Master, the kid has been taken by the authorities
看样子他这么做没什么阴谋
Doesn't seem there's any treachery
好像没有
Unlikely
可能跟著那个疯和尚闷死了
Perhaps he's been bored to death by that crazy monk
好了，我们回去了
Let's go back
是
Yes
把她拉进去，好大的胆子，想偷走
Take her in. What a nerve, want to escape
王老爷，这个想偷跑的女人
Master wang, we have apprehended
我们把她抓回来了
the girl who wanted to escape
抓回来了？
Really?
王老爷，我求求你放我出去吧
Master wang, let me go please
放你？
Let you go?
如果这儿的女人都放了的话
If all the girls were let go
谁来给我们接客
who'll serve our customers?
是啊，难道叫我妈妈去接客？
Right, would my mother have to do that?
是不是？爸爸
Am I right? Father
少废话
Shut up
王老爷，我求求你
I beg you
把她拉到柴房里吊起来
Hang her in the hut
起来，走…
Go...
六婆，这件事情你知道怎么做
You know what to do
知道了，王老爷，我会办好的
Yes, I'll fix it
谢谢了
Thanks
打死你…
Let me beat you...
你想跑没那么容易
You can't escape this easily
告诉你，王老爷能抓你回来
As master wang has taken you back
你就一辈子在这儿待著
you'll spend your whole life here
我没什么对不起王老爷的
I haven't done anything wrong against him
我求求你
I beg you
我管不了那么多
It's none of my business
总之这儿是进得出不得，小老虎
Once here, you can't get out. Tiger
在
Yes
三天三夜不给她东西吃
Starve her for three days
水都不能让她喝，看她服不服？
no water either; she'll yield
是
Yes
等一等，阿三，进去看著那间柴房
wait, go and guard the hut
我去？
Me?
谁都不准进去
No one is allowed inside
大爷，别客气…多吃一点
Sir, have some more...
姑娘你一定很饿了，赶快把它吃了
You must be hungry, go on
我不想吃
I don't want to
大嫂，谢谢你救我出去吧
Please help me to get out
我救你？
Me?
我一辈子关在这儿没关系
It doesn't matter if I have to spend my life here
但是我的孩子
but my kid!
你还有孩子？
You have a kid?
他才八岁，好可怜
He's only eight, poor thing
没有人照顾他是不行的
he needs someone to care for him
原来你也是那么惨的
You are that pathetic
小福禄害死了我丈夫
Xiao Fu Lu killed my husband
目的就是想捉我来这儿
for getting me here
他太残忍了，太没有人性了
He is a cruel beast
救救我吧，大嫂
Save me, madam
我求求你做做好事，救救我吧
Please do a good deed
我…
I...
现在只有你一个人可以救我
Only you could save me
大嫂，我求求你
I beg you
我这一辈子都不会忘记
I'll never forget your favour
你的大恩大德，大嫂
the rest of my life
大爷，吃得怎么样？好不好？
Sir, how about the dishes?
救命啊…
Help...
什么事？
what's up?
她跑了
She's escaped
跑了？追
Chase
救命啊…
Help...
你是谁？在我们后门口干什么？
who are you? What are you doing here?
我…
I...
你让人打了？
You've been beaten?
是啊，他们还要捉我
Yes, they also want to capture me
我无路可走
I have no way to go
所以走到这儿来躲一躲
so I hid here
这儿又不是客栈
This is not an inn
怎么躲？
how can you hide here?
不如我暂时留在这儿帮你干活吧
Could I stay and work for you?
不要工钱的
Free
不要工钱？
For free?
只要你肯收留我就行了
As long as you let me stay
不要工钱，这倒不错
Not a bad idea
马上洗碗
wash the dishes then
好
Okay
等等，拿碗汤进去煮两碗汤面
wait, go in and cook some noodles with soup
面来了
Here are the noodles
慢用
Easy
鸡汤面
Chicken soup noodles
今天的面味道特别好，多吃点
It's tasty, eat more
大师，刚才那碗鸡汤面真是好极了
That bowl of noodles was really good
那两个和尚一边吃一边夸奖你
The monks praised you as they ate
不关我事
I didn't make it
你说那碗是什么面？
what kind of noodles was that?
鸡汤面
Chicken soup noodles
什么？鸡…
what? Chicken...
那是她做的
She cooked it
这个人是谁？
who is that?
她是我新来的下手，不收工钱的
A new helper, working for free
就是这间，进去
This is it, go in
起来…
Get up...
大爷，这儿已经有人坐了
Sir, this place has been taken
大爷我不喜欢
I don't like to sit there
本大爷喜欢坐这儿
I like to sit here
老兄，我们还没吃完
Sir, we haven't finished
你怎么那么不讲理？
You are so unreasonable
什么讲理，这个就是理
what the... this is my reason
伙计
waiter
来了来了
Yes
大爷您要吃什么我给您预备
I'll get you whatever you prefer
您随便要
Feel free to order
想吃什么？先请你吃这个
I want to start with this
诸位…各位朋友听我说
Friends, listen to me
不要吵…有事好商量，不要吵
Please stop, let's work this out
别吵，有什么好吃的？
what's good to eat?
你想吃什么我们这儿什么都有
We've anything you ask for
我想吃狗肉
I want dog meat
狗肉？天还没凉，迟一点才有
Sorry, it's only served in winter
我们这班兄弟三天三夜没吃饭了
My brothers haven't eaten for 3 days and nights
你可帮我照顾照顾他们
Please take care of them
行，没问题，一定办到…
No problem at all...
去你的
Damn you
如果你来得慢今天你就有麻烦
If you are slow, you'll be in trouble
不会慢的，马上就到
Right away
我们吃了那么多油腻
we've eaten so much meat
今天晚上吃点素的不错
it's best we had a vegetarian meal tonight
今天晚上我就不吃素了
Not for me
咱们走，走…
Let's go...
各位…怎么这么快就走了？
Folks, going so soon?
还没算账呢
You haven't paid
算账？算什么账？
Pay for what?
多谢光顾，一共是七钱四分半
Altogether 74 cents
臭小子你听著
Listen, you bastard
你想到我们这儿来占地盘
you want to do business in our turf
你跟我们江湖朋友讲钱
And you talk about money to us, huh!
够不够义气？
That's not good
那就不是这么说了
Not really
那该怎么说？
what then?
如果人家肯施舍给你们
If it was a charity
那就用不著给钱了
then you needn't pay
但是你们大摇大摆进来吃完就走
But you come in here so arrogantly to eat then leave
道理上似乎不大对
it doesn't seem right
你敢教训我们？
You dare lecture us?
不是
No
给他点厉害看看
Teach him a lesson
不要动手…
Stop...
怎么回事情？
what's the matter?
三爷
Master Yin
他们那帮家伙吃了东西不给钱
They ate but wouldn't pay
还要打我
and they hit me
算了…
Forget it...
什么算了？
Forget it?
各位都是我不好，请…算了
It's my fault, please... forget it
走了…
Let's go...
三爷，他们吃了好多东西
They ate a lot
就这么放了他们？
should we let them gojust like this?
算了…这帮人是从外地来的
Forget it... they are from elsewhere
没有弄清楚千万不要乱来
Don't be rash without knowing their background
他们这么乱来我不会饶过他们的
I'll not let them get away easily
轻一点
Be gentle
你叫什么？
what's your name?
他们叫我三娘
They call me San Niang
几岁了？
How old are you?
二十六
Twenty six
为什么让人打？
why did they hit you?
丈夫死了
My husband's dead
欠人家钱就给捉进去妓院
I owe money and was taken to a whore house
妓院？老头，什么叫妓院？
Old man, what's a whore house?
妓院就窑子
A whore house is a brothel
那什么叫窑子？
what's a brothel?
窑子就是男人去逛的地方
It's a place where men frequent
男人逛的地方？
where men frequent?
那我也可以去见识见识
Then I should go there to have a look
老头，一块儿去吧
Let's go together, old man
我这么大把年纪了
I am so old
你为了不肯进窑子就跑出来了？
So you escaped since you don't want to go there?
我是为了我的孩子
It's for my kid
你的孩子？
Your kid?
他叫小三
His name is Xiao San
到现在我都不知道他在哪儿
I don't know where he is now
你的命真是苦啊，行了
You've had a miserable life
老头
Old man
我从来都不知道女人这么有用的
I never knew a woman could be so useful
是吗？你从来都不知道？
Really? You didn't?
我是在和尚庙里长大的
I grew up in a monastery
我怎么知道女人会伺候人
how'd I know women could serve men
娘…
Mother...
小三
Xiao San
我来看你
I've come to see you
你怎么会找到我的？
How did you find me?
我四处找你
I looked all over for you
后来那个算命的告诉我你是在这儿
The fortune teller told me you were here
你快点走吧，这儿是不能留你的
Go quickly, you can't stay here
我一天都没有吃过东西
I haven't eaten for a day
娘，有没有饭吃？
Is there food to eat?
你等一会儿
Wait
快点拿回去吃吧
Take it and eat
有没有猪肉？
Any pork?
没有
No
有没有鸡脚？
Chicken legs?
当然没有了，这儿是素菜馆子
Of course not, this is a vegetarian restaurant
娘，我那么小你就要我吃素？
I'm only a kid and you want me to eat vegetarian foods
你快点走吧
Leave
我明天会送碗回来的
I'll bring back the bowls tomorrow
你千万不要回来了
Don't come back at all
还有你自己待在家里
Stay at home
我会想办法照顾你的
and I will think of a way to take care of you
谢谢娘
Thanks, mom
大师，我找到线索
Master, I got a lead
怎么样？
well?
今天来这里捣乱的那帮人
The guys who caused trouble today
真是由黄梅镇来的
came from wang Mui town
是谁请的？
who hired them?
是本镇的坏蛋阿头
Head of the scoundrels in this town
阿头？他是什么人？
who is he?
他是王昌槐手下的第一号走狗
He is the bastard who reports to wang Chang Huai
王昌槐？又是这帮王八蛋
Those bastards again
就是因为他打不过你
As he is no match to you
所以才请了这帮人来这里捣乱
he hired those ruffians to cause trouble
不错，但是我得先去找他们的阿头
I'll get to their leader first
对，这个家伙在本镇欺压良民
Right, this guy has oppressed
无恶不作
our people
连要饭的钱他都抢
He has even robbed the beggars
那我就更需要去拜访他一下
Then I need to pay him a visit
是谁找我？
who's looking for me?
好像是那个小疯子
That Crazy kid
他找我？
He wants me?
荣爷，我看他来意不善
Master wing, I think he comes with bad intention
让不让他进来？
Shall I let him in?
他有没有带人来？
Is he alone?
就他一个
Yes
他有没有带家伙？
Has he brought weapons?
没有带，你看我两手空空的
No, see, I am unarmed
小疯子，你凭什么闯进来？
why have you barged in here?
你知不知道这是什么地方？
Do you know what place this is?
我知道这是你阿头的地方，是吗？
This is your turf, right?
我今天特地来拜访你的
I have come specially to pay you a visit
你知道我一定会见你？
You know I will see you?
你现在不是见著我了吗？
Aren't you seeing me now?
不要疯疯癫癫的
Stop your crazy act,
说，找我干什么？
what do you want me for?
我来这儿是打听一件事
To find out something
听说前两天那帮来我店里捣乱的人
I hear, the gang that caused trouble in my restaurant
是你为王昌槐效劳的，是不是？
was hired by you, right?
你这个狂徒原来是来这儿捣乱的
So you have come to stir up trouble
赶他出去
Kick him out
是，走…
Yes, go...
那么没礼貌，你怎么赶我走
Kick me out? So impolite
动手
Fight
打我？
You dare hit me?
叫他们走开，不然勒死你
Ask them to move away or I'll kill you
上
Attack
走开…
Move away...
疯大爷
Crazy sir
你是不是要我赔偿你店里的损失
do you want me to compensate you for your damages?
我赔给你
I'll pay you
损坏我店里东西的钱那就算了
There is no need
不过这样
But I want you to
现在我要你把打家劫舍得来的
cough up the loot you have robbed
金银珠宝全部拿出来
along with all the jewelry you took
荣爷，别听他的…
Master wing, don't listen to him
叫他们走开
Ask them away
走开…
Move away...
疯大爷，你拿这些东西干什么？
what do you want with these things?
拿出来去分给镇上所有的穷人
To give to the poor
什么？
what?
你是要钱还是要命？
Do you want to live?
要命…我要命
Yes
走，快点来…
Go quickly
快点，走…
Move...
放好了
Put it down
你看那个疯子
The Crazy kid
把那个大贼抓回来了
has taken that robber back
那个小疯子可真够厉害的
He is really something
你现在对著这么多叔伯兄弟
Now, in front of all our neighbours and brothers
你可以认罪了
you can apologise
我认…
Okay...
说
Speak
各位，我这个没用的贼头
Folks, I am a useless robber
历年来打家劫舍，仗势横行
I have robbed and oppressed people
打穿了老百姓的头
I broke their heads
还打伤了老百姓的腿
I broke their limbs too
我真是作恶多端罪该万死
I deserve to die
我该死该死，我该打该打
I really deserve to die
行了吧？
Is this okay?
不行，你最要紧的话还没说
No, you have left out the most important part
说不说？
would you speak or not?
我说…
Sure...
各位，现在我把历年来
I'm going to return to you all
搜刮的东西还给大家
everything that I've robbed
好…
Good...
各位静一静…
Please be quiet...
现在由阿头的几个手下
Now his men will personally
亲自把东西还给大家，打开
return the property to you all
不许乱动
Don't move
小朋友，你要钱来干什么？
Kid, what do you want the money for?
我当然要了
Of course I want it
我有了钱
If I have money
我就可以救我妈离开这个地方
I can rescue my Mom from this place
那你妈在什么地方？
where's your Mom?
我不知道
I don't know
不过我妈说那儿是火坑来的
but she said it's a fire pit (place for prostitute)
火坑？那不给烤死了
Fire pit? She'll be burnt to death
我们快去救她，快
Let's go rescue her, hurry
上哪儿去救？
where to?
你带我去
You take me there
我怎么知道火坑在哪儿
How would I know where it is
你真是个小疯子
You are such a crazy kid
你别跑，不要走
Don't run
你们为什么不叫手下帮那个头？
why don't you ask the men to help the chief?
老爷，那个疯子人虽然小
Master, although that Crazy kid is very young
可是他的功夫好得不得了
his kung fu is great
连头的手下都不是他的对手
Even the chief's men are no match for him
是啊，爸爸
That's right, Dad
头自己也让疯子一手抓住了
He too was grabbed by the Crazy kid
动都不能动了
and couldn't move at all
老爷…王老爷
Master... Master
这么晚了什么事？
It's late, what is it?
逃跑的那个三娘
That San Niang who escaped...
已经查到她的下落了
I know where she is
在什么地方？
where's she?
她在疯子开的那间素菜馆里面做工
She's working at the vegetarian restaurant
又是他，又是这个小疯子
That crazy kid again
等我马上去把她抓回来，走
Let me go and grab her back, come on
慢著，对付这种人要暗中来暗中去
wait, we have to do this in secret
是
Yes
现在外面几更了？
what time is it now?
刚刚打完二更
It's just after the second watch
你听著，四更以后
Listen up, make it after the fourth watch
什么事？
what happened?
大师，三娘失踪了
Master, San Niang has disappeared
是吗？
Really?
是，今天我一早起来就不见三娘
I haven't seen San Niang since this morning
还有后门也给人打开了
The back door was open
而且我又在这儿捡到这个
Besides, I picked this up in here
大师，照这个情形看来
Master, looks like
三娘一定是给人捉去了
San Niang has been kidnapped
我知道，我以前也见过这样东西
I know, I've seen such things before
又是你，臭小子
You again, bastard
又是你
You again
你别拦著我，我有要紧事情
Get out of my way, I've urgent business to attend to
我也有要紧事，我妈给人捉去了
Me too, my mom has been kidnapped
是你妈？
Your mom?
不错
That's right
那她叫什么名字？
what's her name?
我叫她妈，人家叫她三娘
I call her mom, other people call her San Niang
什么？三娘？
what? San Niang?
我刚要赶去救她，走
I'm just about to go rescue her, come on
你又怎么知道你妈让那帮人捉去的
How do you know who has kidnapped your mom?
又是那个算命的跟我说的
The fortune teller told me
你会不会功夫？
Do you know kung fu?
会一点
A little bit
我爸爸没死的时候教过我跟我妈妈
My late father taught me and my mom
露两手
Let's have a look
行了
Alright
我看你倒不会让人家乱拳打死
I suppose you won't be beaten to death by others
走
Let's go
两位少爷，早
Masters, good morning
各位早
Good morning
谁呀？小少爷怎么那么早就来了
who is it? How come you are so early?
是啊，加开早场
That's right, a morning show
真是太好了
That's good
不知道有没有相熟的姑娘？
Is there some girl you prefer?
有，他也有
Yes, he's got one too
这么小的少爷就会出来玩了？
So small, he's just a kid!
那我们这行想不旺都不行了
No wonder we'll have good business
是啊，旺了
Right
两位小少爷想找哪位相熟的姑娘
Any particular girl you have in mind?
三娘
San Niang
三娘？就是那个偷跑了
San Niang? The one who ran away
后来给我们抓回来的那个？
and was caught by us
不错
That's right
就是她了
It's her
你看看这位姑娘多有号召力
what a charming lady she is
正所谓老少咸宜
young and the old alike like her
是啊
That's right
不知道两位要找哪位姑娘？
which lady are you looking for?
他们说要找的是那个
They said they want that one
要三娘
San Niang
是啊，她在哪儿？
Yes, where's she?
就在那间房子里
Inside that room
我们去看看
Let's go and have a look
少爷…等一等，你们等一等
Master... wait...
开门…来人，快
Open the door... hurry
什么事？
what is it?
快开门
Hurry and open the door
这怎么得了，她现在还不能接客
She can't take any customers right now
快点跟我出去
Follow me out
怎么出去？
How?
你跟著我好了，快点
Just follow me, hurry
拦住她，别让她跑了，快拦著
Stop him, don't let her go
上下左右，左
Up, down, left, right, left
娘
Mom
快点走
Hurry and go
快
Hurry
这边，这边走
This way
爸爸
Dad
小疯子这样搞法，我们怎么混下去
we can't do business if Crazy kid goes on like this
是啊，老爷
That's right
自从尹振邦那王八蛋
Since that bastard Yin Chun Bong
请了疯子来了以后
hired that Crazy kid
我们王家的地位就受到了威胁
our position has been threatened
而且还处于挨打的地位
and we are in a disadvantageous position
爸爸，你快点找人收拾他才行
Dad, hurry and find someone to take care of him
知道了
Okay
我心里有数
I know what to do,
你们不用心急
don't be rash
对付这种人要软硬兼施，双管齐下
I know how to tackle his kind
爸爸，你的意思是…
Dad, you mean...
大宝
Da Bo
在
Yes
拿我的请帖请小疯子到这儿来
Send my invitation to the Crazy kid
请他来？他肯不肯来？
Invite him? Will he come?
用我的拜帖他一定会来的
With my invitation, he sure will
来…再来，过来
Come on... once again
喝了吧
Drink it
他们两个挺不错
They get along well
喝了它吧
Drink it
擦擦
Rub it
尹三爷，趁热多喝几杯吧
Master Yin, drink more while it's hot
好，谢谢你，三娘
Alright, thank you, San Niang
三娘，我想跟你谈一谈
San Niang, I'd like to talk to you
什么事？三爷
what is it?
你觉得疯大师这个人怎么样？
What do you think about Master Crazy?
三爷，你真是的
What are you talking?
好了，带他去洗个脸吧
Take him to wash his face
疯大师，过来喝一杯吧
Master Crazy, have a drink
好，谢谢
Thank you
来，喝
Come, drink
小三这孩子真是可爱
Xiao San is really cute
是吗？
Really?
是
Yes
你觉得三娘这个人怎么样？
what do you think about San Niang?
三娘，好极了
San Niang, great
我跟老头说过
I even told the old man
我从来都不知道原来女人这么有用
that I've never known women could be so useful
所以三爷想跟你们两个人这么样
Master Yin wants to do these for you two
干什么？
what is it?
疯大师
Master Crazy
三爷的意思是成全你们两个
He means for the two of you to be together
把三娘嫁给你
and let San Niang marry you
嫁给我？
Marry me?
疯大师
Master
这件事情我始终没有敢跟你说
Never mentioned this to you before, because
因为我怕她配不上你
I was afraid she mightn't be good enough for you
因为她是一个寡妇
I mean, because she's a widow
寡妇？寡妇倒无所谓
widow? There's no problem about it
大师，她已经嫁过一次了
Master, she's been married once
嫁过一次？不是更好
Married once? That's even better
最低限度就用不著摆酒那么铺张了
At least there's no need for any wedding banquet
三爷，你说对不对？
Is that correct?
对…对极了
Correct...
还有，她还有个孩子叫小三的
And, she's got a kid called Xiao San
你说那个孩子
You mean that kid
难道你不在乎？
wouldn't you mind being called 'father'
一进洞房就有人管你叫爸爸了？
once you married her?
这有什么关系
That's no big deal
我动也不用动
I don't need to do anything
马上就有人叫我做爸爸了
yet someone's already calling me Dad
你们各位听著，我现在是买一送一
It's buy one, get one free
还不便宜，是不是？…
It's a bargain, isn't it?
过去
Let's go
喝
Drink
疯大师，我们王老爷有请
Master Crazy, our Master wishes to invite you
你们王老爷…请我干什么？
Invite me for what?
我不知道
I don't know
不过有件造福地方的事
but there's something that could bless our place
请你商量一下
which he'd like to discuss with you
造福地方的事？
Benefit our place?
三爷
Mr. Yin
疯大师，这件好事你一定乐意做的
Master, I'm sure you'll be more than willing to do this
请你就去吧
Please
这样？好，我跟你去
Alright, I'll go with you
大师…
Master...
三娘，什么事？
San Niang, what is it?
你可别去
Don't go
王昌槐笑里藏刀，专门害人的
wang Chang Huai is a smiling villain
你放心好了，我心里自然有数
Don't worry, I know what to do
请
Please
请，请坐
Have a seat please
听说大师的功夫一流
It's been heard that Master's kung fu is great
地方上没人是你的对手
no one could match you in this place
哪里哪里
Oh, you're too kind
其实我这种人根本就不会功夫的
Actually I don't know kung fu
你太客气了
You're being too modest
谢谢
Thank you
请用茶
Have tea please
喝茶
Please
对了，王大爷今天请我来…
You invite me to come here today for...
你知道本地是不出产盐的
You know that this land doesn't produce any salt
所以价钱很贵
that's why the price is high
搞得那些老百姓负担很重
And the burden eventually falls on the people
是啊
That's right
刚刚好我有一批盐想运到邻县去
I've a salt shipment for the neighbouring province
以低价卖出以益民生
I intend to sell this cargo cheap to benefit the people
没错，这真是一件大好事
That's right, this is indeed a good deed
好事就不敢说了
Don't mention it
总算是造福百姓
it's just for the benefit of the people
不过这批盐的数目不小
But this shipment is not a small one
恐怕沿途被人抢劫
and I'm afraid that it'll be robbed
所以想请大师…
so I'd like to...
我明白了，你是想请我做保镖
I see, you want me to escort it
不知道大师有没有意见？
Any objection?
这个嘛
Well...
不要紧
Never mind
如果大师没有胆子的话那就算了
If you don't have the guts, then forget it
有…有胆子
No, no... l'm willing to do it
好，我先替地方上的百姓多谢你了
Alright, I thank you on behalf of all the people
不用客气，那我们就这样决定了
No problem at all, it's a deal
至于酬劳
As for the remuneration...
这件事分文不取
I'll take nothing for it
那太谢谢了，谢谢…
Thank you...
哪里…
No problem at all
送客
Please see our guest out
请
Please
Bye
老爷
Master
那些官兵我已经全部联络好了
I've contacted all the officials
没有麻烦吧？
Any problems?
没有
No
好极了
Good
这次我看这个小疯子
Let me see how
还跑到哪儿去
this kid can get away this time
快点快点
Hurry
来了
There they are
盐来了…
The salt is here...
过来…到这边来
Come over... over here
各位我叫你们带来换盐的东西
Have you prepared the things
准备好了没有？
to replace the salt?
准备好了
Yes
是不是好东西？
Are they good?
好东西
Good
好，各位，各位叔伯
Alright, every one
现在你们大家把那些盐先分好了
Divide the salt
好…
Okay
你们分好了盐之后
After that
把带来的东西换进去让我们带回去
replace the stuff and let us bring it back
他们来了
They are here
不要动，大家不要动，包围他们
Don't move, surround them
是
Yes
你们这帮家伙
You've been caught
这次可给大爷我捉住了吧
by me this time
大爷，你为什么要捉我们？
Sir, why are you arresting us?
为什么捉你们？
Why arrest you?
大胆的私枭，公然贩运私盐
You smuggler, how dare you smuggle
还大摇大摆地走过
salt openly?
我看你们这次是死定了
You're dead
什么？我们贩运私盐？
what? We smuggle salt?
你知不知道
Do you know
这个年头贩运私盐是什么罪？
what's the charge for smuggling salt?
是什么罪？
What?
死罪
Death penalty
什么？死罪？
what? Death penalty?
捉贼捉赃，大家动手
Check their stuff, move
大爷
Sir
我们上当了
we've been trapped
搜到东西没有？
what have you got?
我们上当了
We've been trapped
上当？
Trapped?
这不是盐
This is not salt
让我看看
Let me see
这些是什么东西？
what is that?
这些是猪尿
Pig's piss
猪尿？
Pig's piss?
大爷，我都说这些不是私盐了
Sir, I told you this is not smuggled salt
我还没说清楚你怎么就这么冲动
You're too rash, I haven't finished yet
不要吵
Quiet
各位，我们到海里洗干净
we'll wash it in the sea
不要走，站住
Don't go, stand there
好小子，你都算厉害
Bastard, how dare you
弄那么个圈套来害我爸爸
set a trap to fool my father
什么圈套？
what trap?
长官都喝了猪尿了
Officers drank the pig piss
你还敢假装糊涂？
and you still dare pretend?
猪尿？不关我事
Pig piss? None of my business
是他自己抢著要喝的
He took it himself
还敢顶嘴
Dare talk back
让我给你点颜色看看
I'll teach you a lesson
揍他
Beat him up
站住…
Stand still...
好小子
Bastard
让我来
Let me do it
鸡胡一番，平胡一番，自摸五番
I'll kill you
诈胡
No way
这死疯子
This Crazy kid
这回可把他们整惨了
They are in real trouble this time
好极了…
Great...
像王昌槐这样的人
we should deal with people
是应该这样对付他
like wang Chang Huai in such a way
是啊，所以我说
Right, that's why I say
如果镇上没有像疯大师这样的人
if the town doesn't have people like you
就不灵了
then it would be bad
这算得了什么
This is nothing
三娘，你去哪儿？
San Niang, where are you off to?
我去拿点酒给你们喝
To get you drinks
等一等，你过来
wait, come over
我们今天晚上
we have come tonight on purpose
特地到这里来为你们做一件事
to do one thing for you
为我们做一件事？什么事？
what? What is it?
我明白了，是不是叫三娘嫁给我
Is it to ask third Madam to marry me?
对了
Right
过来
Come over
我妈嫁给了他，那我怎么办？
what about me if my mom married him?
大师，这点小意思
Master, a small token
是我们大家捐出来送给你的
from us all to you
送给我？
For me?
是啊
Yes
干什么？
why?
这点银两是送给你们办喜事
The money is for your marriage
三娘嫁给我还要办喜事？
I should arrange a celebration for the marriage?
是啊，买点新的东西布置新房
Yes, get some things to decorate your home
谢谢各位
Thank you
老板，就要这么多了
Boss, enough?
大师，干嘛这么早？
Master, you're early
我要娶三娘了，现在办嫁妆
I am buying stuff for the marriage
恭喜恭喜
Congratulations
谢谢，总共多少钱？
Thanks, how much?
早…我要娶老婆了
Good morning... I am getting married
那真恭喜你了
Congratulations
谢谢，早
Thanks, morning
早，这位就是三娘
This is San Niang
我就是要娶她做老婆
she is to become my wife
那就该恭喜你了
Congratulations
谢谢
Thanks
大师，娶老婆
A monk... getting a wife!
三娘，我们今天晚上洞房了
San Niang, we'll consummate our marriage tonight
不知道
Don't know
对了，三娘，洞房是怎么回事？
San Niang, what's that all about?
都说不知道了
I said I don't know
你骗我，你以前嫁过丈夫洞过房
You lie to me, you were married once
你怎么会不知道
you should know
你真讨厌
You're a nuisance
三娘，我都不怕羞了你还怕羞
San Niang, you shouldn't be shy
三娘，我们现在洞房
San Niang, let's do it now
再等一会儿
wait
你怕他们还没走？我出去看看
Are you worried they are still here? I'll take a look
三娘，外面没有人了
San Niang, there's no one outside
等一下，先把蜡烛吹灭了
wait, blow out the candles
是，吹灭了蜡烛
Yes
就不会让人家看见我们洞房了
then people can't see us
他会不会关上门打我妈妈
would he lock the door and beat my mom?
小三，早点睡，别吵了
Xiao San, be quiet and sleep early
我已经睡著了
I am asleep
睡著了怎么还会说话？
Then why are you still talking?
什么？娶三娘成家立室
What? Marrying San Niang?
我看小疯子那家伙
I believe the Crazy kid
真想在这儿生根了
is going to settle down here
老爷，我早就说过
Master, I did say it earlier
这些就是尹振邦那班人的阴谋
that this was the plot of the Yin Chun Bong
是啊，爸爸，如果这样搞下去
Yes, dad, if this goes on
我们不是连一点威风都没了吗
we'll lose face
不要吵，爸爸我心里有数
Quiet, I have a plan
吴祖德
wu Zu De
是，老爷
Yes, master
你还记不记得南山县
Do you still remember that ruthless
那个杀人不眨眼的梁山耀
killer Liang Shan Yao?
梁山耀？我记得了
Yes
就是那个连自己亲娘都杀了的恶霸
That's the man who even killed his own mother
爸爸，我记得小的时候
Dad, I remember when I was small
你不是请他办过一件事
you asked him to do a task for you
不错，就是他
That's him
一不做二不休
I'll be ruthless and ask him
我就请他回来对付小疯子
to deal with the Crazy kid
走…
Let's go
不要杀我…
Don't kill me...
有话快说，是谁让你来杀我的？
Speak, who asked you to kill me?
谁？
Who?
是陈老坚
Chen Luo Kin
陈老坚？他为什么要这么做？
why would he want to do that?
因为…
Because...
说
Speak
你杀死了他两个心腹，所以…
You killed two of his men, so...
混账，杀人是我的职业
Nonsense, to kill is my profession
我杀他的心腹，我有我的代价
I was paid to do it
你回去说给陈老坚听
Go back and tell him
如果有一天有人收买我杀他
if someday someone pays me to kill him
我也照办
I'll do it
是…
Yes...
因为我收人家钱财就要替人消灾
I am paid to do this for a living
走，快走
Go quickly
没错，梁师傅说得对
Master Liang is right
受人钱财替人消灾
One must do one's job after getting paid
你们几位又是谁来著？
And who might you be?
梁师傅，我们是来自邻县南山镇的
We are from Nan Shan town
这次专门拜访你
we have come to pay you a visit
是因为我们王昌槐王老爷有请
Our master wang Chang Huai has an invitation for you
请坐
Please sit
梁师傅一路上辛苦了
Master Liang has had a long journey
哪里…没有…
It's okay
梁师傅，我们喝一杯
Let's have a toast
喝，大家喝
A toast
谢谢
Thanks
请…
Please...
王老爷，听说这个地方搞得很乱
I hear this place is unruly
究竟是不是真的？
is it true?
如果是假的就不必请你来了
If it weren't true I wouldn't need you here
难道连你自己都吃了亏？
You've had trouble yourself too?
不，我们还没动手
No, we haven't made a move yet
依你王老爷的身手
Based on your skills
为什么不试几招把它踩平了
you could resolve the issues
当然可以
Of course
不过王某人在地方上
But I enjoy a
都算有点名望的人物
bit of fame around here
怎么可以跟那小无赖随便地动手呢
It isn't right for me to condescend and resort to a fight
所以我们王老爷特地请你来帮忙的
That's why our master has sought your help
三拳两脚就把他打倒了
It's an easy task
好了，既然王老爷这么瞧得起兄弟
Right, since you have so much faith
就把那个什么小疯子交给我吧
leave that Crazy kid to me
他哪里是什么和尚
He is no monk
前两天才娶了老婆
he just got married a few days ago
什么？他真会享福
what? He really knows how to enjoy life
是啊，他差点把我爸爸气死
That's right, he's driven my Dad mad
他娶的老婆就是妓院里偷跑的三娘
He's married San Niang who escaped from the brothel
照你们那么说他胆子倒不小
I see, so he's got a nerve
小三，上哪儿去？
Xiao San, where are you going?
整天坐在这儿闷死了
I'm so bored sitting here all day
我想出去玩玩
I want to go out
好了，没事做就出去玩吧
Alright, go out if you have nothing else to do
不用整天坐在这儿
No need to sit here all day
还有你长大了以后
Besides, when you grow up
千万不要学你爸爸那样
Don't become a chef
做伙头大将军
like your father
知道了
I understand
大师，两碗豆腐汤面，要快点
Master, two bowls of noodles in tofu soup, hurry
"Ying Chun House"
梁师傅，请
Master Liang, please
我们迎春阁的姑娘可漂亮了
Our ladies here are beautiful
看什么看，有什么好看？
what are you looking at?
自从你来了以后，你看
Since you are here, look
这小子他是谁？
who's this kid?
他就是那小疯子的拖油瓶
He's the stepson of the Crazy kid
斩草除根
Kill him
梁师傅，王老爷重金请你来到这儿
Master Liang, Master wang has paid heavily to hire you
你得先来个下马威给王老爷看看
you should show how good you are
喝了吧
Drink
三娘…快出来，快点出来
San Niang... come quickly
小三…
Xiao San...
谁是凶手一定会查出来的
we'll find out who the murderer is
大师，你放心好了
Master, don't worry
我们一定会查个水落石出的
the truth will come out
不用查了，我心里有数
Don't bother, I knew it
大师
Master
我心里好像起了杀机
I have an urge to kill
大师，你要冷静一些
Master, stay calm
我本来不应该起杀机的
I shouldn't feel this way
但是小三那么小，他们居然…
but Xiao San is so small and yet they...
我现在怎么办呢？
what should I do now?
大师不要难过了
Don't feel bad
其实三娘比你更难过
San Niang feels even worse
你应该安慰她才是
you should comfort her
我知道
I know
对了，三娘呢，她去了哪里？
where is San Niang?
放开我
Let me go
梁师傅
Master Liang
这个女人我是特地用来孝敬你的
This woman is for your pleasure
皮光肉滑
She's real nice
想不到这疯子福气倒不错
The Crazy kid is fortunate
小福禄，你害死了我的孩子还不够
You not only killed my son
还想再害我
you want to hurt me as well
这是什么话？
what are you saying?
你这臭婆娘
You bitch
你那小鬼是给老鼠咬死的
Your bastard was bitten to death by rats
怎么也赖在我头上了
and you want to lay that on me
你可别乱说话
Mind what you say
除了你这王八蛋还有谁
who else apart from you could it be?
那可冤枉大老爷我了
False accusation
我小福禄连蚊子都不拈死一只
I have never hurt a fly
何况孩子
not to mention a child
伙计  在
- Men - Yes
把那臭娘们绑在凳子上
Tie up that bitch
让梁师傅好好享受一下
let Master Liang have a good time
是
Yes
梁师傅你今天晚上可以尽量享受了
Master Liang, you can have a good time tonight
我还可以中个四重彩呢
I could get lucky too
我的妈
Damn
她有腿功，挡著她
Her legs are powerful, careful
想走？
want to run?
三娘呢，三娘回来没有？
Has San Niang returned?
她还没有回来
Not yet
三娘…
San Niang...
快点快点
Hurry
三娘
San Niang
快点走啊
Go quickly
快走
Let's go
三娘…
San Niang...
是谁干的？是谁？
who did this? Who?
小福禄
Xiao Fu Lu...
小福禄，又是他
Him again
小子，以后不要再发神经病了
Don't lose your mind again
住在这儿你当过瘾
You think it's good to stay here
你知道什么
You know what?
师傅说一人做事一人当
Teacher said one must be responsible for one's actions
你师傅？
Your teacher?
就那个素菜馆的大师傅？
The Chef at the vegetarian restaurant?
你别糟质我师傅
Don't insult my teacher
我告诉你小子，你师傅娶了老婆了
Your teacher has taken a wife
什么？我师傅娶了老婆？
Really?
胖子，师傅，老头
Fatty, teacher, old man
师傅…我回来了
Teacher... I am back
师傅，是我，小黑呀
Teacher, I'm Xiao Hei
师傅，我今天出狱
Teacher, I'm out ofjail today
到处找钱买点礼物送给你
I'm trying to gather some money to buy you a present
师傅，听说你娶了个师母是不是？
I've heard that you've got married
是
Yes
那太恭喜你了
Congratulations
师母现在在哪儿？让我见一见
where's Madam? Let me go and see her
你见不到她了
You won't see her
为什么？
why?
她已经…
She's already...
师傅，她怎么那么快就死了？
Teacher, how come she died so quickly
难道她给人家…
Has she been...
不错，她是被人害死的
Yes, she's been murdered
是谁？
By who?
除了那个王昌槐还能有谁
Who else if not wang Chang Huai?
又是他，他们现在还那么无恶不作
Him again, he stops at nothing
师傅，我去给师母报仇
Teacher, I'll avenge for Madam
不行
No
不报这个仇我就不是你徒弟
I won't be your student if I don't seek revenge
回来，你不能去
Come back, you can't go
我就去
I am going
小黑，你不要去
Xiao Hei, don't go
师傅，你就让我去吧
Teacher, let me go
我不让你去
I can't let you go
我非去不可
I must
你不能去
You can't
你放手
Let go of me
我就不放手
I won't
小黑，你不能去，你打不过他们的
Xiao Hei, no, you are no match for them
打不过，我就跟他们拼命
I'll fight with him until death
你快放手你
Let me go
你不能去
You can't go
小黑…听师傅的话
Xiao Hei, listen to me
我次次都听，这次就不听
I always listen to you, but not this time
什么？听话
what? Be good
放手，你
Let me go, you
小黑…你不能去，小黑
Xiao Hei... don't go
一，二，三
One, two, three
王昌槐，你出来，出来
wang Chang Huai, come out
你杀死了我师傅的老婆
You've killed my Teacher's wife
今天我要杀死你们
I must kill you all today
大师…
Master...
是不是小黑他…
Is Xiao Hei...
今天一早天矇矇亮
Early this morning
小黑的尸体
Xiao Hei's body
就给人从王昌槐的家里扔了出来
was thrown out of wang Chang Huai's home
他…
He...
他死得好惨，连肚子里的东西
He died tragically
都给他们用刀挖出来了
he was disemboweled
大师，王昌槐这帮人实在太可恨了
Master, wang Chang Huai's gang is notorious
他们先把小三杀了
First they killed Xiao San
然后又害死了三娘
then San Niang
现在又打死了小黑子
and now it's Xiao Hei
大师，你应该还手
Master, you should fight back
在这个地方忍是没有用的
There's no point tolerating all this
为了你，他们死得好惨
Because of you they all died tragically
以后还不知道要死多少人呢
God knows how many more will suffer the same fate!
为什么你还不还手呢？
Why don't you fight back?
大师，为什么…
Master, why?
对，对，我为什么不还手？
That's right, why didn't I fight back
我为什么要忍？我为什么？
why should I tolerate all this? Why?
我应该开杀戒，我不可以再忍
I must start killing, I can't tolerate any more
我要杀人
I must kill them all
王昌槐，我要杀死你…
wang Chang Huai, I must kill you
王昌槐，我要杀你…
上
Attack
"Buddha"
"The endless power of Buddha"
"Just repent and salvation is at hand"
站住
Stand still
出身佛门竟然滥杀无辜
You're a monk, how can you kill people
你的所谓的大慈大悲到哪儿去了
where is your mercy and forgiveness?
王昌槐
Wang Chang Huai
你们这样做迟早是会后悔的
You'll regret what you've done
你们的残暴
No one can tolerate
是任何人都忍受不了的
your endless cruelty
像我这种人
People like me
我早就应该把你杀了
should have killed you a long time ago
不错
That's right
但是你们的残暴逼得我忍无可忍
Your cruelty has pushed me to the extent
逼得我没办法不开杀戒
that I must break my vow not to kill
杀吧，还有一个我，过来杀
Go on then. Come on, kill me
现在我不想杀你了
I don't want to kill you now
什么？你说什么？
what? What are you talking about?
我不想把你们这帮禽兽杀光
I don't intend to kill you guys
我要你们回头是岸
I want you to repent
回头是岸？
Repent?
但是你现在就回不了头
But you can't go back now
轮到我来杀你了
I have to kill you
WWW.52HALFCD.COM
时代影视论坛 荣誉出品
谢谢收看！再见